me and we'll have our invocation from pastor of new beginnings, live church,
mr. Jonathan Jennings.
All right, well first I want to write a quick, I just want to read from Roman chapter 13 verse 1 and it says every person is to be in subjections of the governing authorities.
There is no authority except from God and those who which exist are established by God.
You know I'm one of those guys that still believes in what the Bible tells us.
I've done about probably 15 years of study to know that we can actually still believe what these scriptures say.
If anybody has me doubt with that they can ask me and so what we have standing before us right here are God appointed men to lead the city of my own.
And as that I hope and I pray my prayer is that each and every one of you take that responsibility on your shoulders for the betterment of our community.
And I personally know bless Parker and I know it's hard not to lead that is the case.
And so that's the reason why I find joy and honor in being here today to pray for you guys. That's great.
Father, we just thank you Lord for the ability to have men that would take the weight of responsibility on their shoulders to stand up and try to produce economy.
Father God, finances, Lord for the communities around us, Lord, places for our children to play.
But everything that the community wants in desires, Lord, falls on the shoulders of these men right here.
Father, I pray that they would not listen to the voices of the enemy as they try to make these decisions or there's a right decision and there's a wrong decision.
But some people will go against the right and some people will go against the wrong.
Some people say, turn left, some turn right.
But Lord, I pray that you would just speak to these men.
Give them the strength and the wisdom to guide the city, Lord God so that we can benefit as a community and Lord as churches in this community.
Father God gives us the ability to pray for these men.
For the guidance not only of our city, but even further into our state, into our country.
Father, I thank you for this opportunity and we pray all of this and then use those Jesus Christ.
Amen.
I'll play with you two to the flag of the United States of America and to the Republic for which it says one nation.
I've heard of it in the visible, with the liberty of justice or all.
For the Republican but unscathed personal appearances.
Five consent agenda.
Staff recommends we approve.
I have a six and seven.
Second.
Third.
Eight.
Davis Wright.
Command.
Planes for GRDA Realizing.
May your members of the council, you will find in your pack at a purchase order related to the
Pensacola Realizing Project in Rule Curve, to DWT, in the amount of $38,000 and $55.85.
They are the end response to some of the stuff that's come about since they responded to them.
Yes.
I say that with some hesitation because this would have been last month's bill.
Okay.
I'll make a motion to approve.
I'll second.
Parker?
David?
Dougal?
Paul?
They'll cost $18,710,953 for materials, $4,730,774 for other services, and a capital outlay of
$2,725,220.
No, these are overall total numbers until you've got more detail than what I'm saying.
It's broken, yeah, yeah, it's broken down more.
I was hoping you gave me a sheet for $3,931,8.
In transfers of $11,735,410 for an overall total of $43,621,698.
Councilmen in May are this is a balanced budget for MSU-A.
There have been no material changes from the meeting we had on April 25th when the council
met and we thoroughly reviewed and discussed the preliminary.
So if you all have any questions of myself and certainly with Jill's help, would be happy to answer any questions you might have.
I don't see anything you own here for streets would that be in the transfer?
Streets would be in general fund.
In the administrative district.
The district now like that.
How much?
It's in the transfer of the letterment of the transfers.
500,000 from the administrative rate.
So that was just about the administrative rate, not the whole budget.
So what she's talking about is the transfer from MSUA towards that from the street now we find.
And then I'll talk about the total amount for streets in the general fund.
I don't have any other questions on that.
On that on that one.
On that one.
I don't think so.
You're going to do them all or just this one.
Just this one.
Okay.
Then we'll do the other one in the council.
This.
All right.
Submer.
Double.
Parker.
Tim.
Contract with TSPI for utility billing print and mailing.
The birthday girl.
Yes.
Perched in here.
First off, there was a smoothing issue.
You guys will see this agenda on the next council meeting.
This contract is for MSUA as well as the city council.
We did not realize that tells it.
Since 2007, a customer service center has used
a pair of immigrant corporation to print and mail
utility bills.
In the past few years, we had experienced some issues with their service.
And as part of our due diligence to get the best quality of service at the
Best surprise, we issued an RP.
TPSI came back significantly.
Rank number one under merit.
And they were tied for second on cost.
Paragrant, which is who we use currently.
They did come back.
There's number one on cost.
But like I said, we have had quite a few issues with them.
And you don't have to.
other print companies have for customization for the utility bills and their communication
is not where we would like to see either.
So staff recommends approving the contract with TPSI.
What's the cost difference?
The packet in detail, it lists out the price here, 4TPSI, the finished bill, 4TPSI is going
to be 0.153 and pair of grant came back with 10 cents, so about 5 cents per bill.
Another of you think other things to note, TPSI is the only proposal that fully complied
with our requirement of this initial format.
They also are the only Oklahoma company and we did a time to mail test for all of our
people that participated in the RFP and TPSI, mail nurse to us on May 23rd and we received
it in house on May 25th, so it was a two day mail time and then pair of grant,
mail nurse on Wednesday, May 18th and we did not receive it anywhere between Saturday and
Monday.
We did not get it in the office until Monday for there, so three to five days, SPC was another one
that participated and took them six days to get our mail to us.
I do want to say two right now, we are paying them approximately 20 cents per bill whenever
they sent in their bid, they did a very much lower price than what we are currently paying them,
so we should not actually see much of a price increase from what we are paying now if we
got the TPSI.
We will get for this a higher level of confidence and greater flexibility in what we can produce
on the bill, which part of our overall goal is to provide more transparency to our
customer.
Peel bill, but more information on the bills.
So I have actually before we knew that we had to do an RFP, we actually thought this was just
a service.
So I had been in contact with TPSI, we have actually already got a new bill from that drafted up and
we will be a lot more detailed, a lot more wine items, we will be able to list out what each individual
charge is, we can put different emails on there, there is a lot more options of what we can
do with the bill, and third communication, I mean they are on it, we literally within three
days they had this whole bill completely done, and we send them in it, you know, modifications
and we get back with them like hours.
If your agreement is not the same way, and we want to make changes that takes about a couple of weeks
to even get a change made to our car bill.
In some of the issues that we've had with Pyrogram that have been significant, I wasn't
here for this one, but it was a big, ordeal.
Pyrogram actually sent out my limited utility bills on coffee bill at the head, and so that happened
in 2019.
And since I've been here, we actually combined, so somebody has a property, and they received
multiple bills for different properties.
We've combined them into one envelope to say, on postage, when we run the process of that,
they somehow missed 117 customers receiving their second bill, so that was just one
of the other.
Is she the one who had just in the last few months?
Why did you shop?
Hey, man.
Any other questions for Kelly?
I want to say that I appreciate that for your putting in the building office, the changes
are being made are good and they're positive, and that reflects in the way the customers
talked to us.
So I don't get nowhere near the calls I used to, so I appreciate it.
I'll make a motion to approve.
All right.
Thank you.
11.
Another new business opinion, which is a reason for posting of this agenda, 12 staff reports, 13
trustee community announcements, and 14, this meeting will be continued from council chambers
and reconvening the staff room for the purpose of executive session at the completion of the
agenda item 17 of the regular meeting in the city council.
Now we'll call it the order of the regular scheduled meeting for the Modesty Council for
Monday, June 6th, 2022.
Public hearing on the proposed fiscal year 2022-23 budget, note this public hearing is called for
any member of the public to present to the gathering body, comments, recommendations, or information
on any part of the proposed budget.
And we've wanted a three proclamation declaring, go do I got to close that public meeting area
in there.
Certainly, you can do that, maybe.
Well, this is one of I had to do.
Yeah.
There were no public, the business will just reflect there is no public comment.
Okay.
Three proclamation declaring June 7, 2022 as State Farm Day.
State Farm is celebrating 100 years.
So, Nate Long from down at the State Farm here in town,
called and talked to me about it.
So we got a proclamation for them.
He couldn't be here tonight.
He's out of town.
So what's the percentage of him at the letter date?
But tomorrow's going to be State Farm Day, my am I.
As long as we approve that, I guess.
Do we have to approve it here?
Yes.
I'll see you there for a little.
Second.
David.
All right.
Stunberg.
Hi.
Four.
Public input.
We're on schedule personal chances.
We have Mr. Beckard Jim.
Look.
Give it to the Association.
Right.
Each year in danger.
And I'm really sorry to say that you made that list for the second time.
And we're not even a retirement.
Maybe that was for number 10.
And it means that we're in danger.
And lots of times it danger things.
You can't do anything bad.
We have the heavy metals coming down track for every day.
Every day.
And what we're asking you in the public to do is to ask the agencies that have some choose
to choose some power to actually do a number either of them understand them.
And to come together and work together on the whole issue.
So we're asking EPA from FEMA and she had to sit down and consider the whole issue.
Because what happens is it's our free doesn't stay you.
It stains us and it stains on us.
But it ends up in green light and against them.
It's a fish that you like to eat.
And it also ends up in the drinking.
And to help all of them.
So I have some handouts for you.
And I'm going to ask you to consider a resolution to do and ask these agencies.
For example, to work together.
I also have some sample letters.
Okay.
Anyone should want to write a letter.
You can do that.
who's contact is right here on the back.
How they're some samples for you.
And I want to thank you very much for installing the sign of a long-term treatment.
I really do.
I'm sorry, I had to be replaced and put it in more permanently.
But there are some other areas that may need those signs.
You know, the train terminal for the children was going to basically.
And so they must not have come by the sign that are surely there.
No.
And I'm very thankful that PQ is sick.
I believe neighbors to, I think, six thousand residents here.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Five.
Consent Agenda.
Stafford remains week.
Approved six and seven.
Second.
Circle.
All right.
Davis.
Eight.
Budget them.
Twenty two.
Twenty seven.
Main Street.
MSUA Airport.
General Administration.
Wastewater collection.
Closing out of fund.
Receipt.
Band.
Grand funds.
Receipt.
Expand.
Oklahoma Water Resources Board.
Jump.
You're not.
He's on vacation.
For this person.
It's a four part commitment.
We're closing the Main Street.
Grand fund.
It literally has a penny in it.
So we want to do that.
The next part is receiving an extending $6600.
It was a reimbursement for education from the Puri at Tribe.
The airport fund is receiving an extending some FAA grant bodies.
And then wastewater collection is receiving an extending the reimbursement of the WRB line.
I'll make a motion to approve.
Sorry.
Parker?
Aye.
So, go for it.
Davis?
Aye.
I understand.
Benjamin 22-28.
MDRA.
Facilities call them.
$3.50.
From the general fund to the MDRA fund,
basically the call them.
It's for elevator maintenance.
We don't have that one up here anyway.
No, it should be in the back.
Okay.
That'll pull.
Hi.
Sumber.
Davis?
I'm sorry.
Parker.
Aye.
10.
fiscal year 22-23 municipal budget message.
And resolution regarding the city of Miami, Oklahoma budget.
So, fiscal year 22-23.
Establishing budget amendment authority.
So, Mayor, members of the council, as you just noted,
in your packets, you have a copy of the fiscal year 22-23 fiscal year budget.
For the general fund, in this case, since we've already talked about the M.S.U.A.
This part is just the general fund.
As you all know, this has been a topic of several ongoing team meetings and discussions,
including my, my city council, the mayor and city staff.
We began the budget process this year evaluating five-year averages to help
calculate the appropriate revenues and expenses.
I'd like to state for the council in citizens.
What is being presented today is a balanced budget.
Regarding the general fund overall projected revenues total $20 million,
$100,946.
And the projected expenditures total $20 million,
$64,321.
This includes transfers in totaling $8 million, $82,192.
Although we finished the fiscal year really strong.
There were many revenue discussions with staff in council,
whether this level of sales and use tax revenue income is an anomaly or...
sustainable. There are many volatile factors, of course, that influence the tax revenue growth,
such as COVID related spending, medical marijuana revenues, and federal relief spending,
which are very all very unpredictable in the coming fiscal year. The good news is we have many
levers that we can pull on throughout the year. There's next fiscal year in the event. We see signs
of a significant downturn in the economy or recession. And let me assure everyone we will be watching
the numbers very closely and we won't hesitate to bring the council in a minute budget if needed.
That being said, the council's direction was pretty clear and that was this is the time to bet
on ourselves. And so with this in mind, we are making changes related to sports tourism and CBB to further
support making my am a destination for entertainment and tourism. These are pretty significant changes.
Additionally, we are putting a primary focus on employee retention and recruitment this next fiscal year.
Over this past year, we have certainly struggled as many have with around 10% in overall job vacancy.
This has been really tough on employees in on morale. To say the least, we are currently contracting with a
third party to perform a salary study, which will be evaluating to apply a market adjustment
across the organization for wages. In addition to personnel, other expenses discussed include
$443,141 in materials, and $1,949,471 in other services and charges. In transfers of $8,494,295 for the overall
projected total expense budget of $20,064,321. As I mentioned earlier, capital improvement plans
requested for this general fund came in at $2,295,354 of which we paired down and prioritized to fit a budget
now at $669,178. Infosystems was placed on life safety issues as a top priority. Finally,
one of the primary requests by the council was that there would be a focus on streets. The budget before
you represents $3,241,018 in street repair and replacement, thanks to one time,
there had been no material changes from the last time that the council met on April 25th to review and
discussed preliminary budget, and I'd be happy to answer any questions you all might have.
One, the line item, so as a establishing budget and minimum authority, can you explain that to us, please?
I'm trying to figure out if you're not going to meet your been.
Sorry, I'm meeting.
So what that gives the city manager authority to transfer money inside of a fund?
So inside the general fund, we can transfer money from one department to another, one line item to another inside of the same department.
You can't transfer money from fund to fund.
Like, emission-vage in a fund.
You couldn't do that. That would be a pleasure to admit.
And as you know, we do that often.
As need be, we have additional funds in one area, but we've decided we want to move them, then that's when we'll come to you.
And you'll see, like, you saw the budget in that earlier, that will come to the council to do those budget amendments.
That process will remain.
So, nothing will change.
Okay.
Congressman, come on over here.
Yes.
Okay.
So if that process won't change, those are pointed putting that in there.
I think it's standard language that's in there.
It's not the authority to actually move money.
Like, I'm going to say, PD and fire didn't last year.
PD and fire, or if the parks has money, he's moved to facilities.
He has the authority to beat that.
So if the budget says we're going to spend this much money, he can't change that.
But he can move all this money inside.
Just move it around inside that fund.
Because I have it all day.
Let me do this.
And then you reconcile it with these.
If we do, do you, ladies?
Yes.
It'll be a budget amendment.
Or if we want to move money from one fund to another and issue a to.
Or rainy day.
If we want to move rainy day to purchase something in the capital improvement.
That's amendment.
The council.
So in this case, even my capital improvement is a separate from from the general funds.
So if we were going to move money from capital improvements to the general fund.
Those are the general fund for some of the purpose we have to come to the council.
rainy day.
It's a separate fund.
The balance.
I don't want to quote myself.
It's on there.
So this time next year, 6.30 of 23 for estimating it's going to be $5,499.798.
There'll be some interest in there, but we don't budget the budget.
Basically $5,500.
Yeah, the question is for Jail on the budget.
I'll second.
Davis.
All right.
Herker.
Simbert.
Don't go.
Hi.
I'm just standing again.
11.
Gays are better.
But the auditor is in associates for services to conduct the fiscal year 21-22 audit.
It was the last time I was in, we need to do this.
We need, we buy state statute.
We have to engage an auditor within 30 days of the end of the fiscal years of budget
like 31st.
I just like to clear them with.
Last year this time, we went out for an RFP for a three year RFP.
This is the second of the third year, our legislator is the one we recommended and you
agree with.
So we're asking you to approve the second of three years with our legislative audit this fiscal
year 21-22.
Now, we'll tell you, I've been very impressed with our legislative audit.
This is actually a group I was not familiar with as I have been with some of our other third
party fiscal firms, but I've been very impressed with him and I have even learned that
the state department of accounting uses the same folks when they have special audits that
they want to do at the state level, the college and associates who they utilize.
And I can see why they've been very professional, very available in very knowledge, make
no sense to approve.
Sand.
Sandberg.
Don't go.
David.
Marker.
12.
Renewal contract between the Audit of Accounting and the City of Miami to provide dispatch services
to Audit of Accounting.
Back in November, we started dispatching countywide through the Miami Police Department at that time
on Accounting provided funding for two dispatchers that existed contract carriers through the fiscal
year.
So this is just an extension of our agreement where we're building now.
The price would go up about $5,000 or $88.5 now, and that's just for flex, married, raising and
parades for our dispatchers.
So, we're still providing two dispatchers to work at the City of Miami Police Department in our
dispatch center and we provide countywide dispatch services.
This has come to an excess with you.
I'll make a motion to approve.
Thank you.
Parker.
Hi.
Sandra.
Davis.
Uncle.
Thanks Chief.
13 procedures for that coming town hall public meeting.
We're going flood issues.
So you have it your respective seats.
A proposal that I worked on.
I have David helped me with the IT parts of it.
Melissa helped me from their perspective.
This is to modify our procedures that we have in place for public speaking at a council meeting.
Because the very nature of this proposed meeting will be significantly different than what we normally do.
One of the main points of that whole meeting will be to hear from the public.
And so this is the proposal that we have put together.
There are two parts of it that are highlighted for you.
Just wanted to make sure that we have this the way that you want it.
Obviously we can change anything else that is in here.
But the two things that were the most significant after we discussed all of this and how it's actually going to work.
It is whether they're the speakers are going to be limited to three minutes.
And then if they are limited, whatever their limited is, is if they say something that may cause a response from either the council members or one of the other speakers that is at the meeting.
Does that time count against them.
As part of their there are a lot of amount of time to speak.
We would submit that it should simply because otherwise it make it almost impossible for for instance for David to be turning off and on the timer.
And somebody is going to think it got started too early or waited too long for somebody else and not them and on and on.
So so those are the major questions that we wanted to make sure that you all are satisfied with.
But obviously anything else in here is certainly something that we can change if you don't like some aspect of it.
It is a significant deviation from what our normal routine council meetings policy or procedure is.
So are the speakers that are coming there to address
how are many of the citizens?
They're limited to three minutes?
Not the agendas speakers.
The public, we will have the agendas speakers
get their spills.
We had some timelines that were really trying to hold them to.
But a main part of the whole meeting is to hear from the public.
We hope that there's a lot of people there.
We don't.
The reason we ultimately set on the three minutes first of all,
that's what we thought you told us.
But second of all, we want to make sure that everybody that wants to talk
gets the opportunity to do that.
And we can't have somebody taking up the amount of time
that's allocated for everybody just being used up by one person
or a few people.
It does allow them to just say what they want to say.
If that's all they're wanting to do,
it does allow them to ask a question.
But they only get one question.
At the end of that, they can go back to the back of the line
and work their way through again.
And again, that's what we were understanding
was what you all thought would be the best way to handle that.
How many agenda do people are we anticipating?
There's five agenda.
And the mayor will be starting the meeting as a regular council meeting,
so that you all can vote on these modifications to the rules.
Then we're going to have five speakers in there.
Three of those speakers will be the mayor in two past mayors,
which have a short time.
There will be a lot of the other two attorneys
that have presentations that they're going to be giving.
And then I've got a five-minute intro in there.
I think that I'm going to do probably right after a blast.
It calls the meeting to order sets of rules.
And then I'll do a welcome and kind of talk the public through the agenda,
do introductions, and then turn it over to our first speaker.
The idea is that we can get through it right now.
I think we can get through most of the presentations
within the first hour.
And then that leaves us an entire hour for a Q&A.
There's 20 people.
If things are perfect.
All right.
We're a faster.
But the third in line, they get to ask question.
So we may be there.
I think a tremendous response if you've got 20 people to offer to the line.
That says I'm here in 9 o'clock.
The third in line.
That I thought they're more to get in line.
But they're already in line in the queue.
They get to ask the same as the question.
So we might be able to get into the line.
And we may give the audience an opportunity if they want to leave the can.
So not holding anybody hostage, certainly.
But everybody that we've talked to that's coming to present or answer questions,
is willing to stay as needed.
So you want to ask about on this tonight?
We would like to because number one, we want to, if it is what you all are
improving.
We want to send it to the other speakers so that they'll be aware of that.
We also want to get it out to the public so that the public will be aware of it.
You know, we talked about if they want to bring something for you to see.
We address it.
We address it one way if it's something as simple as a piece of paper or a photograph.
But we have to have to deal with it differently if it's something that's going to be loaded
onto our computers.
We don't want to infect our computers on and on.
So in order for the public to be aware of this, we want to get it out as soon as possible.
How much emotion do I prove?
Don't go.
All right.
Davis.
Sumber.
Hi.
Parker.
Mr. Mayor, I'll eliminate these highlights and have a finished product.
So are you going to agreement by that notion that we are once they start, they got three minutes.
Right.
Okay.
I think that's right.
That is one of the other methods.
Yes.
So I'll have that finished for you.
So you can sign it tonight.
Definitely can get it out.
All right.
Fourteen.
Now the new business of any, which is the reasons of the posting of this agenda.
Fifteen staff reports.
Fifteen, mayor, counsel, community announcements.
Since I ripped on them last year, I'm going to brag on them this year.
Cemetery folks, got to grasp no dish here, despite the monsoon and got to give credit
where credit is due.
It looked really nice.
I have a couple here, a young lady that goes to my post schools, lost it in the last
day.
I'm growing like my first name.
But she came up with the idea about the door locks for the schools and there was a great effort
and every door we got covered.
This was an elementary school student at Craig, that came with this idea and I thought it
was pretty entrepreneurial of her to start that project and see it through.
That's it, Holland Lawson and so I wanted to mention her, which one of the one I had
with was a little like I may just have to do it next time.
Yeah, I think.
All right, 17.
This meeting will be continued from the Council Chamber's Reconvening the Staff Room, the
purpose of executive session.
After the completion of the agenda item, it ended in the out of 15 of the regular.
He probably is discussing executive session under contract.
So moved.
Thank you.
So, what?
Hi.
December.
Davis.
Hi.
17.
Her 18.
Her German.
So moved.
So, what?
David.
Hi.
Parker.
Now, we're convening the Council and the Council chambers of the regular city council
meeting and action on the matters of dressing executive session, which will be the contracts
of Chuck, I'm going to like the last line here.
Chestnut.
That's written and Boris and Ben Loring as amended.
Motion.
Second.
So cool.
Hi.
Summer Davis.
Parker.
Hi.
21.
See you in my interest communications.
I do not have anything additional there.
22.
Jump it.
So moved.
Thank you.
Michael.
Hi.
Davis.
Parker.